NGUYEN HOANG VIET

Mobile Software Engineer (Junior)

0398 560 520







ABOUT MYSELF

I am working as a Mobile Developer (React Native) with more than 1 years of experiences. Recently, I've been doing more research on Flutter and have worked on several projects that use the Bloc pattern.

I am so welcome and happy to learn, to share and to talk about IT knowledge.

I always try to practice to improve all my skills (Tech, life, ...), everything new that make myself better everyday.

github.com/vietnguyenhoangw in linkedin.com/in/vietnguyenhoangw

WORK EXPERIENCES

Mobile developer

ITBee-Solutions | 11/2020 - Present

Working as mobile developer.

- The main person initiating the project, base config (Redux, Restful Api, Base Components...), building the source's structure, merge code, resolve the React-native problem with team's members..
- Join and learn Swift to maintain iOS project with mobile project manager.

Internship / Fresher Mobile developer

Ant-Tech | 05/2020 - 10/2020

Internship process as mobile dev position.

- Using React-native with Hook, Redux Saga, folder constructed according Ignite boilerplate. How to upgrade new React-native's version, upgrade new library's version.
- Using TypeScript / ES6 syntax, refactor code for looking more clean
- · More Git skills: Stash, revert, merge, config handle
- · Build new Android and iOS (Xcode) version, build and test Android bundle with bundle tool
- Daily report, meeting skill, write report document, resolve the problem...

Student / Working with my teacher

The first time to join and work with real project. Understanding the process of product (from initiation to release) working with BA, dev. tester, designer...

- My first meet with React Native, Redux / Redux observable, Components, Props / States, React Native's lifecycle
- JavaScript syntax, how to working (run, debug...) with React Native
- · Apply Git's skills to manager real project's source code

TYPICAL PROJECTS



Project Description: BeeBeauty is an application with mains feature are Spa schedule booking, sell products, remember customer's information for Spa chain system.

Mobile team size: 3

Responsibilities:

- Mobile project's leader (Assign tasks, resolve problems train for team members. Error handler in development process...)
- Initiate project, config base (Redux, Redux-Saga, Service, build folder structure following Ignite pattern, create common base components...)
- Fix bug, refactor code and manager source code with Git (Merge code, Conflict handle)
- Build iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab).

Inside the project: Ignite pattern structure, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, Hook, react-native-config, one-signal...

AnyBackup

01/2021 - 02/2021

Project Description: AnyBackup is an iOS IOT application using with auto-backup device (can connect with USB or SD card) to backup or restore data (photos, musics ...) from iPhone to auto-backup device and vice versa.

Mobile team size: 2

Responsibilities:

- · Research, Build UI and feature following customer's requirements
- Fix bugs, refactor code, build new version..

Inside the project: Swift 5, SnapKit, MVC design pattern



Project Description: Polymate is a social network which has the particularity of relying on a news feed developed by its own users, which changes in real time taking into account the geolocated position of the mobile

Mobile team size: 4 (in Viet Nam, reference: polymate.fr/nous)

Responsibilities:

- Support and recommend the way to resolve the problems, new feature ideas directly with client.
- · Build new screen, working with Restful API.

SKILLS

Technical

Mobile Applications

React native / Flutter

Redux / Bloc

JavaScript / TypeScript / Dart

Worked with iOS / Swift

Self Skills

Effective communication

Team player

Problem solver

Knowledge

Understanding about the Product Management Process

Understanding about software design, some design pattern, RestfulAPI

EDUCATION

Software Engineer

Ho Chi Minh City Vocational Training College

LANGUAGES

Vietnamese (Native)

English (Reading, Basic Speaking, Writing)

INTERESTS

Reading, Watching, Listening

Badminton

Photography

ACTIVITIES

15km Finisher

LAAN Ultra trial 2019 (2019)

- $\bullet\,\,$ Fix bug, refactor code and manager source code with Git.
- Build iOS version to TestFlight and Android (apk, aab).
- Write documentation for future maintainers.

Inside the project: Ignite pattern structure, Redux-Saga, TypeScript, Hook, react-native-config, one-signal...



PERSONAL PROJECTS



English Vocab

Project description: I have developed this application for play mini game to learn english. This application can login with Google account, message together and available on Google Play now (in the process to develope new version with Flutter).

Project's target: Working with SQLite to save and query data, crawl data with Jsoup, Google Services to develope message, notification feature...

Improve logic handle skill and mindset to resolve the problems.

Deploy app to Google Play and more...

Reference: Available on Play Store



SocialNetwork

 $\textbf{Project description:} \ This \ application \ have \ features \ same \ with \ another \ social \ application. \ User \ can \ manager \ user's$ profile and see new post create new post...

Project's target: Init application from zero, build folder structure following Ignore pattern. Working with restful API, custom components, how to integrate npm popular package, build version...



You can find more my personal projects was public on My Github (+50 repositories). All of them are developed when I have free time or after my work hours for the purpose of practicing skills or learning